Contact

Block: B, Road no: E/1, House no: 188, Eastern Housing 2nd Phase, Pallabi, Mirpur-1216 +8801915811114 (Mobile) rubelshak@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/md-mazedur-rahman-8432ba57 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Back-End Web Development AngularJS Microsoft Azure

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Bangla (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

C#, MS SQL Server, and SQL

Honors-Awards

Best Executive-2014

Md. Mazedur Rahman

Lead Consultant PL/SQL

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Summary

I wanted to engage myself as software development professional in the field of Informational Technologies

(IT) where my knowledge; education and experience of Information Software System Security; Software

Development; Networking; Hardware Management Knowledge can be utilized that enable me analytical,

technical, and innovation skills to support and guard organizations Information Technology Management.

Experience

Midas Software Solutions LTD Lead Consultant PL/SQL June 2022 - Present (1 year)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Developing, maintaining and implementing Banking solutions with ORACLE FLEXCUBE.

ChefOnline Partners
Software Engineer
June 2021 - May 2022 (1 year)
United Kingdom

Currently working in EPoS system.
Using C#.net, SQL Server 2014, nodejs & MongoDB.

Youngones Bangladesh Assistant Manager (Software) March 2020 - June 2021 (1 year 4 months) Chittagong, Bangladesh

Customized Inventory Management System (Desktop & Web Based)
Using C#.net, AngularJS, Java, JavaScript, RDLC & SQL Server 2016.

Base Textiles Limited.

3 years 1 month

Sr. Asst. Manager (HRIS)
July 2018 - February 2020 (1 year 8 months)
Chittagong

- # Scanning and Assess Vulnerability of Organization Server, Network and Client PCs.
- # Assess and Organizations Software Security before Implementation.
- # Time to Time Audit Organization Data Center to Assess Vulnerability.
- # Sample Based End User IT Visit for Ensuring Compliance with IT Policy.
- # Protect Organization from Insider and Outsider Threats.
- # Ensure Data Security & File Security and Ensure Regular Data Backup.
- # Establish and Monitor Secure Data Communication Between Two Offices.
- # Follow-up New Threats to Organization IT Infrastructure & Stretch Proper Remedies.
- # Planning, Designing, Budgeting & Implementing Organizations IT Infrastructure Defining Scope, Goals and Deliverables as per Organizations Requirement.
- # Planning Scheduling and Monitoring IT Infrastructure Development.
- # Regular Updating Organizations IT Security Police for Adaptive Secure Environment.
- # Take part Implementation of MFI & Others Software in Organization.
- # Supervision of 10 Member IT Team.
- # In addition to other responsibilities as and when assigned.

Achievement

- # Developed Customized ERP Development (Desktop & Web MVC).
- # Developed Customized Quality Inspection System (integration with weight scale device).
- # Developed ERP System for Garments Management System Using C#.NET and Microsoft SQL Server.
- # Developed Inventory Management System (IMS).

Assistant Manager (HRIS)
February 2017 - July 2018 (1 year 6 months)
Chittagong

HKD International (CEPZ) Ltd.

Sr. Executive (MIS)

February 2014 - February 2017 (3 years 1 month)

Chittagong, Bangladesh.

Responsibility

Software Development (Visual Studio 2010, PHP, JQuery, HTML,

JavaScript, MS SQL Server, SQL Server Reporting Tools and My SQL)

- # Maintenance of Redhat Linux Server.
- # Maintenance of Time attendance devices.
- # Support to Offices on Technical Issues.
- # Training for better Implementation of E-Service.
- # Technical Write-up.
- # In addition to other responsibilities as and when assigned.
- # End User IT Support.

Achievement

- # Development Automatic Attendance Download System.
- # Development Human Resource Management System (HRMS).
- # Development Payroll Management System (PMS).
- # Development Provident Fund Management System (PF).
- # Development Inventory Management System (IMS).
- # Development Customs Bond Records Information System (CBRIS).

YOUNGONE CEPZ LTD.

Team Leader-IT (Software)

March 2013 - February 2014 (1 year)

Chittagong, Bangladesh

- # Software Development (C#.Net, MS SQL Server 2008 R2, SQL Server Reporting Tools and MySQL)
- # Implement New Software
- # Maintenance of Existing Software.
- # Support to Offices on Technical Issues.
- # Regular Data Backup.
- # End User IT Support.
- 4|Page
- # In addition to other responsibilities as and when assigned.

Achievement

- # Development Automatic Attendance Download System.
- # Development Human Resource Management System (HRMS).
- # Development Payroll Management System (PMS).
- # Development Provident Fund Management System (PF).
- # Development Inventory Management System (IMS).

Kabir Group Of Industries

Programmer

December 2011 - March 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Chittagong, Bangladesh.

Responsibility

- # Software Programming with, Visual Basic, C#.Net, MS SQL Server 2008 R2,
- SQL Server Reporting Tools, MySQL & Crystal Reports).
- # Organization Requirement Analyst, Support & Liaison.
- # Maintenance of Existing Software.
- # Support to Offices on Technical Issues.
- # Regular Data Backup.
- # End User IT Support.
- # In addition to other responsibilities as and when assigned.

Achievement

- # Development Automatic Attendance Download System.
- # Development Human Resource Management System (HRMS).
- # Development Payroll Management System (PMS).
- # Development Provident Fund Management System (PF).
- # Development Inventory Management System (IMS).
- # Development Purchase Information System (PIS).

SYSCARE Limited

Asst. Programmer

March 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 10 months)

Chittagong, Bangladesh.

Responsibility

- # Software Programming with, Visual Basic, C#.Net, MS SQL Server 2000, 2008, 2008 R2 and Crystal Reports).
- # Customer Requirement Analyst, Support & Liaison.
- # Technical and Financial Project Proposal Preparation.
- # Project Time Schedule Preparation.
- # Client End Software Support.
- # Responsible for project maintenance.
- # Delivered Software to the client site.
- # In addition, other responsibilities as and when assigned.

Achievement

- # Development Accounting Management System (AMC).
- # Development Finance Management System (FMS).
- # Development Sales Management System (SMS).
- # Development Delivery Management System (DMS).
- # Development Attendance Download System, HRMS, PMS, IMS, PIS.
- # Involvement on Successful Implementation of 10 Projects.

Education

Southern University Bangladesh
Bachelor's Of Computer Science & Information Technology, Computer
Software Engineering · (2010 - 2012)

MIPS Institute of Management & Technology Diploma in CSE, Computer Science · (2005 - 2009)

Baitus Saraf Ideal Kamil Madrasha.

Dakhil, Secince · (2004 - 2005)